JOHN TECKEMEYER

johnteckemeyer@gmail.com · 510-673-8723 ·

https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-teckemeyer https://github.com/TheTeck

SUMMARY

The positions that I have held in the past that I have really enjoyed shared the common thread of bringing beauty and art into the world while, at the same time, requiring critical problem solving on my part. I hope to find myself in a position of creating experiences that are stimulating to myself, as well as to others.

SKILLS: HTML ♦ CSS ♦ React ♦ Semantic UI ♦ Materialize ♦ MongoDB ♦ PostgreSQL ♦ Node.js ♦ Django ♦ Express.js ♦ JWT Authentication ♦ OAuth ♦ Full-Stack Web Development ♦ VSCode ♦ Git/Github ♦ Javascript ♦ Python

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Sheet Music Maker | *Solo Concept Project*

Developer | Bay Area | 1-week sprint

- Created a sheet music editor GUI which users can create, modify and share their music
- Developed using React, Javascript, CSS, Semantic UI, Express is and MongoDB/Mongoose
- Used API calls to receive JSON formatted data from the backend
- Provided user security through JWT authentication.

Our Alley | Team Concept Project

Developer | Bay Area | 1-week sprint

- Performing the role of scrum master, I defined and organized the particular tasks needed for us to achieve our goals and distributed duties appropriately for greatest efficiency
- Frontend developed with HTML, CSS, Materialize and DTL
- Was in charge of geocoding locations to locate other users within a certain radius of the user, utilizing the Google Maps API

Barter Town | Solo Concept Project

Developer | Bay Area | 1-week sprint

- Created a network for users to trade their goods with each other through bid proposals
- Backend developed using Node is, Express is, MongoDB/Mongoose and frontend with HTML, CSS and materialize
- Implemented a secure and reliable Google OAuth login with Passport.js

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Development Educator

Instructor

May2021 - Present

- Walked student through every step of each CRUD operation from the frontend in React to the backend where we accessed and modified the database, ensuring they understood what each part of the application was doing and why
- Introduced and articulated the concepts involved with working with React such as hooks, passing props, lifting state and life
 cycle methods

Teckemeyer Luthiery

Owner/Luthier

October 2017- Present

- Significant levels of attention to details critical to the outcome of the product
- Creative problem-solving, coming up with unique solutions to unique problems

Trader Joe's

Crew Member/Section Lead

April 2004 - January 2021

- Demonstrated excellent communication in coordinating with 5 to 20 employees at any given time to accomplish our tasks
- Managed one of the largest sections of the store while simultaneously performing the functions of a regular crew member

EDUCATION

General Assembly

San Francisco, CA

Certificate, Software Engineering Immersive

February 2021 - May 2021

• 12-week training program, full-time, 500+ hours, project-based program taught by industry leaders

California State University, Hayward Bachelor's Degree in Music Composition

Hayward, CA

Graduated '08

• Music theory, orchestration, and multiple musical instrument performance taught by world-renowned musicians

Ohlone Community College

Fremont, CA

Associate's Degree in Natural Science

• Focus on computer science and mathematics

Graduated '02